Mss.970.3.On1 Mss.970.3.On1
American Philosophical Society
Ebenezer Meriam correspondence, 1850-1855
Mss.970.3.On1
American Philosophical Society
32.0 Item(s)
Letters from two young Christian Onondaga Indians, Thomas La Fort and Jameson L. Thomas, about their efforts to get an education so they might help their tribe; from Chief David Hill, leader of the Christian Onondagas, asking for financial and political aid when the New York state legislature refused money for a school on the Onondaga reservation, and when the Christian and pagan Indians sought to divide the reservation between them.
32 items.
Meriam, Ebenezer,1794-1864.
Box 1
Early American History Note
This collection consists primarily of correspondence form Onondaga Indians in the 1850. Much of the correspondence discusses education and religion. Some of the letters relate to affairs between New York state and Indian groups seeking aid. Much of this correspondence is beyond the chronological scope of this guide.
Biographical/Historical note
Ebenezer Meriam was a New York Indian agent.
Hill, David, -- Chief.; La Fort, Thomas; Thomas, Jameson L.; Education; Government Affairs; Indian reservations; Indians of North America--Education; Native America; Native American Materials; New York (State) -- Politics and government -- 1775-1865.; Onondaga Indians
- Papers
  - Broadside Circular, Nov. 21, 1850; Edwards, J. L.
    Scope and Contents note
    T.D. 3p. with Manuscript notes in margin. From Pension Office, explaining that not every letter can be answered quickly and the circular explains what can be expected. Marginal not states "There is nothing due to the heirs of David Hill, who was a chief of the Onandaga Tribe."
  - Letter to Eben Meriam, Nov. 14, 1851; 12-1/4x7-1/2; Hill, David
    Onondaga Castle, L.S. for David Hill by Lyman Beach. 1p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Business. Education for Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York, Jan. 21, 1852; 10x8; La Fort, Thomas
    Cazenovia, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Is studying. Asks for money.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Feb. 9, 1852; 10-1/2x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Cazenovia, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Tells of his course of studies.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, April 2, 1852; 10x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters from Onondaga Indians.) Concerning his studies in school. Need for money for schooling for Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, June 5, 1852; 8-1/2x7; La Fort, Thomas
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. (see letters from Onondaga Indians.) Asks for money so that he might stay in school, although he doesn't like the school in Albany.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, July 2, 1852; 10x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters from Onondaga Indians.) Is going on vaction for ten weeks. Asks that newspapers be sent to the reservation.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Dec. 28, 1852; 8-3/4x7-1/4; Hill, David
    Onondaga Castle, New York, A.L.S.: [written by Thomas La Fort. 3P. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Business. Needs money for clothing for children.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York, Jan. 27, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Thomas, Jameson L
    Rushford Academy, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Difficulties in studying in the school.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York, Jan. 31, 1853; 10x8; La Fort, Thomas
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see letters of Onondaga Indians.) Hopes to hear from him after Feb. 10, when school recommences.
  - Letter to [Ebenezer] Meriam, Feb. 16, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Hill, David
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Needs help in getting the legislature to divide the lands of the Onondaga Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, May 24, 1853; 9-3/4x7-3/4; La Fort, Thomas
    Albany, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Wishes to hear from him and needs support. Wishes there was support for schools for Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, May 28, 1853; 10x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Albany, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Friendly letter concerning his schooling. Sorry that there will be no more appropriations for Indian schools.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, May 31, 1853; 10x7-3/4; Hill, David
    Albany, L. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Difficulty with lands in the Indian reservations.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, July 21, 1853; 8x5; La Fort, Thomas
    Brooklyn, L.S.: Thomas La Fort and Jameson L.Thomas. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Asks for money for train fare back home
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, July 26, 1853; 10x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Onondaga Reservation, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Thanks him for clothes and former favor
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, July 28, 1853; 10x8; Hill, David
    Onondaga Reservation, L. 3p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Needs funds and teacher for Indians. Asks his help.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, Aug. 10, 1853; 10x7-3/4; La Fort, Thomas
    Onondaga Reservation, L.S.: Thomas La Fort, Jameson L. Thomas and [for] David Hill. 1p.and add.,end. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Concerning funds for clothing.
  - Letter to E[benezerJ Meriam, New York City, Sept. 19, 1853; 10x7-1/2; Hill, L A
    Onondaga Castle, A.L.S. 1p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians. ) Writes for David Hill who wishes to know date of his arrival. L.A.Hill commences school for the Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York, Oct. 19, 1853; 12-1/4x8; La Fort, Thomas
    Jonesville, New York, A.L.S. 2p.and add. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) J.L.Thomas to go to school and then can help the Indians. Needs money to visit New York.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Oct. 25, 1853; 9x7; Thomas, Jameson L
    Rushford, N.Y., A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Is in school. Enjoyed his visit to New York City.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York City, Nov. 10, 1853; 10x7-3/4; La Fort, Thomas
    Jonesville, N.Y., A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Studies hard to get a good education to help the Indians. Needs help.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Feb. 27, 1854; 10x8; Hill, David
    Onondaga Castle, L. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Education among the Onondaga.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, March 21, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Thomas, Jameson L
    Onondaga Castle, A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Wishes to visit him in New York City.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, March 27, 1854; 9x7; La Fort, Thomas
    New York, Onondaga Res[ervation], A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Needs to visit him about Indian affairs
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, April 3, 1854; 9x7; Thomas, Jameson L
    Onondaga Reservation, A.L.S. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Wishes to see him.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, May 22, 1854; 10x8; Thomas, Jameson L
    Onondaga Reservation, A.L.S. 1p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Wishes to see him. Concerning Indian affairs on the reservation.
  - Letter to E. Meriam, June 27, 1854; La Fort, Thomas; Thomas, Jameson L.
    A.L.S. 1p.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Nov. 11, 1854; 10x8; Hill, David
    Onondaga Reservation, A.L.S.: "writing Thomas La Fort". 3p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Difficulties in the Indian reservation between Christian and pagan Indians.
  - Letter to E[benezerJ Meriam, New York, Nov. 17, 1854; 9-3/4x7-3/4; Hill, David
    Onondaga Reservation, L.S.: David Hill by Thomas La Fort.(see Letters of Onondaga Indians.)Christian Indians wish to divide reservation between themselves and pagans.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, Jan. 4, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Hill, David
    Onondaga Reservation, L. 2p. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Indian reservation difficulties.
  - Letter to E[benezer] Meriam, New York, Feb. 14, 1855; 9-3/4x8; Hill, David
    Onondaga Reservation, L. 1p.and add.,end. (see Letters of Onondaga Indians.) Indian reservation difficulties.